Mayurkumar Patel

Senior Backend Engineer

mayurt20@gmail.com | Ahmedabad, India

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer specializing in rapid web application development using open source tools. A highly motivated individual who is an expert in Agile project management and has experience in all phases of software development. Application domain experience in car sharing, finance, and social classified.

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End	CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, JavaScript, React.js, jQuery, Ajax
Back End	Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Python, GoLang, GraphQL
Machine Learning	PyTourch, FastAI, Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy
Data Stores	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis
Servers	Apache HTTP Server, Nginx, Puma, Thin, Passenger
Operating Systems	Ubuntu, Mac OS, Windows 10, CentOS

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer | BALANCE IT | Ahmedabad, India

Dec 2017 - Present

BalanceIT is a major player in veterinary products marketplace. BalanceIT developed and supports the full range of Balance IT® clinical nutrition solutions.

- Planning and execution of projects.
- Build and deployed Machine Learning models for Customer Support team
- Developed new architecture for veterinary approval system.
- Implemented Agile Project Development philosophy.
- Implemented automation in testing with Rspec
- Conducted deployment setup using CodeDeploy, AutoScaling Group, and Other AWS tools.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Ruby on Rails, GoLang, Auto Scaling Groups of AWS, Elastic Load Balancer of AWS, CodeDeploy, RDS, EC2, S3, Route 53, ReactJS, GraphQL

Senior Software Developer MATT TALBOT RECOVERY SERVICES | Ahmedabad, India

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Matt Talbot Recovery Services, Inc. is located in the heart of Milwaukee's vibrant central city and has provided sanctuary to thousands of men seeking to address their substance abuse and regain control of their lives.

- Conducted Requirement Gathering.
- Designed Sprint for Project.
- Developed and Implemented Permission Module.
- Managed a team of three developers.

- Setup Test driven development practices
- Implemented Agile Project Development philosophy.
- Configured and managed continuous deployment.
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Nginx + Puma Server, Bootstrap, RDS, EC2, S3, HIPPA Compliance

Senior Ruby Developer | GOBBLE | Ahmedabad, India

Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

Gobble is ready to make a food delivery startup based in San Francisco. It has a whole order management system, payment management, and customer management modules.

- Gathered requirements and provided estimations for tasks.
- Designed and implemented new architecture for Order Placement Module of the project.
- Collaborated with a global team and implemented Test Driven Development (TDD).
- Involved in the development of the order management module.
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Python, ReactJS, MySql, Rspec, Redis

Ruby Developer | FITARD | Mumbai, India

Dec 2015 - Aug 2016

Fitard is India's first platform where you can earn for your fitness activity. We care about your fitness and we are motivating you by giving rewards. Fitard uses Google Fit for getting activity data and do the analysis. It will set your daily goal accordingly and rewards you if you met the goal.

- Was responsible for designing the architecture of the application and designing and managing the schema and database.
- Deployed code to the server and maintain the database.
- Implemented Social Activity Algorithm.
- Was responsible for the implementation of new concepts to help improve the product's user experience.
- Involved in marketing and customer support team.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Ruby on Rails, HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, MySql, MongoDB, Python, Heroku

Ruby Developer | ZIPCAR | Mumbai, India

Mar 2014 - July 2016

Zipcar is one of the early startups in the car-sharing industry and they have 10 million user base across the world. Zipcar has various modules like Registrations, Reservations, i18n and Super Sender. Zipcar initially had a legacy system in ACS framework and they wanted to migrate to Rails. My teammates and I were responsible for creating rails API which will be consumed by AngularJS front end. In the registration module and Market Tool (Admin Panel), we had two databases. We used MongoDB as temporary storage of data and once applications or market approved it is saved to Oracle DB.

- Involved in requirement analysis, client interaction, documentation, and automated testing.
- Involved in complete website redesign implementation.
- Was responsible for managing the team who created API endpoints.
- Implemented Test Driven Development(TDD)
- Involved in Deployments process
- Involved in development of in-house authentication, authorization, analytics and super sender system(all are mainly rails applications)
- Implemented ELK stack
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, ¡Query, Ajax, MySql, MongoDB, Rspec, CentOS, ELK Stack

Trusty Deal was Indian first social classified site. While OLX and Quikr where on top of the classified market, the cases of fraud were increased. It was due to a lack of trust. On the same line Pankaj Singh Bora, Entrepreneur, started his venture named TrustyDeal.com. I was the core team member there.

- Was responsible for designing the architecture of the application.
- Was responsible for Designing and managing the schema and database.
- Was responsible for coordination within my team to develop a hassle-free user-friendly social classified site.
- Implemented Social Connection Algorithm with Facebook login.
- Was responsible for suggesting and implementation of a new concept to help improvise the product's user experience.
- Was responsible for Deployments process.
- Involved in marketing and customer support team.
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, HTML, Bootstrap, ¡Query, Postgres, Ionic

EDUCATION

B.Tech | Chandubhai S Patel Institute of Technology | Changa, Gujarat, India 2013

2009 -

CERTIFICATIONS

RECTJS - BUILD REAL WORLD JS APPS AND DEPLOY ON CLOUD | Coursera.org FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATION | FreeCodeCamp

2016 2016

PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mayurpatidar/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/mayur patidar
Github: https://github.com/charusat09

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/4797110/mayur-patel

Blog: https://medium.com/@mayurt20